Remember...
牢记
There must be something that you always wanted to do but you couldn't.
一定有什么想做但一直做不到的事情吧
There are many things I want to do.
我有很多想做的事
Very good.
很好
Whatever it is, however it is done,
不管是什么事  无论要怎样做
you will start doing it with utmost planning.
都要以做计划开始
You should have daily, weekly, monthly plans.
应该有每日，每周，每月的计划
You won't cut corners. You'll make it complicated.
不要走捷径，要把事情做细致
Dad, don't you remember anything?
爷爷  你不记得了吗？
Dad, I'm getting a divorce.
爸  我要离婚了
I'll introduce you to someone.
我给你介绍一个人
But that's how he works.
但这就是他的工作方式
- Who is he? - That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
-他是谁？-那个卑鄙的记者Ates Arbay
I used to be a fiery and an idealist reporter.
我曾经是一个热情的理想主义者
Oh, poor Agah.
哦，可怜的Agah.
What have you done?
你做了什么？
AFTER 2 AM - CUSTOMERS LEAVE - THE DOORS ARE LOCKED
凌晨2点之后 -顾客离开 -锁门
LIFE BEGINS SIGNED: AGAH BEYOGLU
签名：AGAH BEYOGLU
What do I do with him now?
我现在该怎么办？
They had "Nevra" written on their foreheads. What's with that?
他们的额头上写着“Nevra”，这是怎么回事？
Just a coincidence. It has nothing to do with me.
只是巧合  与我无关
Selim, I actually have a question.
Selim，我有一个问题
Do you know someone named Naimhan Turedi?
你知道有人叫Naimhan Turedi吗？
- Naimhan... - Turedi. Born in Kambura.
-Naimhan- Turedi出生于Kambura
Oh yes, of course I do.
哦，是的，我知道
Yasin used to collect trash over by the garage. He's dead now.
Yasin以前经常在车库里收集垃圾  他已经死了
They had sons. Not good for anything.
他们有个儿子，没什么用处
They all left for Istanbul.
他们都去了伊斯坦布尔
How about someone named Mehmet Yurtgil? A judge.
叫Mehmet Yurtgil的法官怎么样？
- He was assigned to here? - No. He might've passed by, though.
-他被分配到这里吗？-不，他可能已经去世了
I don't remember the name.
我不记得这个名字
Alright.
好的
I'll speak to the guys over at the station.
我要去跟警局的人聊一聊
Come by again, though, this time for dinner.
晚上过来吃饭
Don't even think about going back before stopping by one last time.
你不来的话就别想回去
Sure.
好的
Where's Agah Beyoglu? He's my dad. Where's my dad?
Agah Beyoglu在哪里，他是我父亲
He was discharged.
他出院了
Discharged? When?
出院了？什么时候？
He was right there when I went to sleep. I wake up and he's gone.
我睡觉的时候他就在那里，我醒来之后他就不见了
When was he discharged?
他什么时候出院的？
Ms. Zuhal, your father left in a hurry. He left you a note.
Zuhal女士，您的父亲匆忙离开，他给您留了张纸条
- Dad? - Over here.
-爸爸？-在这
What are you doing, dad?
爸  你在做什么？
How about I don't share the details?
我不分享细节怎么样？
What is this note? Huh?
这是什么纸条？
"I'm going to get the car. See you at the house."
“我要去取车，家里见”
We were worried sick. You should've let us know.
我们都很担心你，你应该让我们知道的
I'm not used to letting people know.
我不习惯让别人知道
I haven't been letting anyone know anything since your mother died.
自从你母亲去世以来，我一直没有让任何人知道任何事情
That's some excuse!
那是个借口！
We were worried sick about you! How about some thoughtfulness?
我们真的很担心你！考虑下我们好吗？
You should really stop shouting. I can't hear you anyway.
别喊了，反正我也听不见
KILLER OR VICTIM?
是杀手还是受害者？
KAMBURA POLICE DEPARTMENT
KAMBURA警察署
Nevra? Welcome!
Nevra！欢迎！
It's me, Vural.
是我，Vural
- Vural? - See?
-Vural -你看
Once someone leaves Kambura, they forget all about their past.
一旦有人离开了Kambura，他们就把以前的事情都忘了
You're hurting me.
你太伤我心了
- Vural. - Yes, Vural.
-Vural -是的，Vural
Sorry, didn't recognize you.
抱歉，没认出你
Of course not. Istanbul is another world.
当然了，伊斯坦布尔是另一个世界
We've been reading all about you on the newspapers, though.
不过，我们一直在报纸上看有关你的消息
I saw you driving earlier today, but you were gone before I could say hi.
我看到你今天早些时候在开车，但在我打招呼之前你走了
Welcome.
欢迎
Thanks.
谢谢
- How's Aunt Nesrin doing? Well, I hope? - Sure.
-Nesrin姨妈过得好吗？-很好
Don't you worry. I'll take care of it.
放心吧，我会自己修的
Excuse me?
什么？
Your door. I'll get it fixed.
车门，我会自己修的
What a shame.
真抱歉
I can take care of it.
我来修吧
Come on...
算了……
You're not coming back to Kambura anytime soon.
你不会很快回来Kambura的
You shouldn't.
你不会的
At least let me pay for it.
至少让我付钱给你吧
Your money's no good here.
你的钱在这里没有用
- Anyway, goodbye. - Goodbye.
-总之，再见了 -再见
Agah! Come out!
Agah！出来！
Isn't Istanbul real expensive? How can you make it with your salary?
伊斯坦布尔房价不是很贵吗？薪水怎么可能付得起？
I make do.
我付得起
Any information?
有任何信息吗？
Can't find anything. He left Kambura a long time ago.
什么都找不到  他很久以前就离开了Kambura
It's been years.
已经好几年了
No info whatsoever since they've left.
从他们离开之后，没有任何信息
But I'll tell the guys to keep looking.
但是我会告诉大家继续寻找
We'll let you know if we have something.
如果有消息我们会通知您
So how do you make it? Do you rent your place?
那你怎么做的？租房子吗？
Agah!
Come out!
出来！
Agah! You can't hide from me!
Agah！你躲不过我！
I'll burn this whole place down!
我会把整个地方都烧掉！
Come on, join us.
来吧，我们一起吃
So...
那么……
Does Kambura feel any different?
Kambura有什么变化吗
Not at all. It's exactly the same.
完全没有，还是老样子
I recall when you used to be a little girl.
我记得你小时候
How old were you?
你那时候几岁？
Ten.
十
I've been courting your mom ever since then. She's never interested.
从那以后我一直在向你妈妈示爱，她一直不感兴趣
I'm not surprised.
意料之中
I'll kill you.
我要杀了你
You're being too much.
你太过分了
Salih...
Come on, let me go.
好了，让我走吧
We can go our separate ways.
我们可以各走各的
Besides, you're wounded. Don't let it get infected.
另外你受伤了，小心感染
You're the one who shot me, you lunatic!
是你先开枪打我，你个疯子！
It was a mistake! It was an accident!
那是误会，纯属意外！
You shot me point blank! How is that an accident?
你直接向我开了枪！怎么会是意外呢？
How did you find me? Have you been following me?
你是怎么找到我的？你一直在跟踪我吗？
Why would I be following you?
我为什么要跟踪你？
My car broke down and you were the first car to come by!
我的车坏了，你是第一辆驶来的车！
It was a coincidence! It was fate!
真是巧合！是天意！
I'm putting the gun away.
我把枪收起来
See?
看到？
I've put it away. See?
我把枪收起来了，看到了吗？
Come on, you put yours away, as well, Salih.
好了，你也把你的收起来吧，Salih
Salih...
Come over and let's talk, brother to brother.
过来，让我们聊一聊
Come on.
来吧
Remember our conversations back in Kambura?
还记得我们在Kambura的谈话吗？
You're like a brother to me. Come on, don't do this.
你就像我的兄弟，来吧，别这样
Salih...
I used to go to the post office every day. Just to see your mom.
我以前每天去邮局只是为了看看你妈妈
I used to send fake letters.
我曾经寄假信件
But I never got the chance to meet her.
但是我一直没有机会见到她
One day, they told me she'd left.
突然有一天，他们告诉我她已经离开了
It had only been six or seven months since she'd started here.
她来这里才六、七个月
- She left so soon. - It was a year. We stayed for a year.
-她这么快就走了 -一年，我们住了一年
Give or take.
差不多吧
I never got to meet her then, but I got her in the end, after all.
之后再没见到过她，但最终我还是得到了
It's delicious.
很好吃
Enjoy.
吃吧
Salih...
萨利赫
Come on, let's have a chat. We're brothers.
来吧，我们聊聊吧，好兄弟
Salih...
Tell me, why?
告诉我为什么？
Why did you come after me after all these years?
这么多年过去了，你为什么要找我？
Why did you try to kill me?
你为什么要杀我？
What did I do to you?
我对你做了什么？
That's funny.
真好笑
- That's what Naimhan asked. - Naimhan?
-那也是Naimhan问的问题 -Naimhan？
What did you do to him?
你对他做了什么？
What did you do to Naimhan?
你对Naimhan做了什么？
Tell me!
告诉我！
Salih, if this is the end of the road...
萨利赫，如果这是我的终点……
Then let me do it.
那就让我自己来吧
- Drop your gun. Drop it! - I'm not dropping it.
-放下枪！-我不会放的
I'll fuck you up! Drop it!
你他妈的快放下！
I won't let you die before telling me why you tried to kill me.
在告诉我为什么要杀我之前，我不会让你死
Tell me, why!
告诉我为什么！
Why were you after me?
你为什么找我？
Conscience.
良心
Conscience?
良心？
What conscience? What does that have to do with anything?
什么良心？良心和这有什么关系？
You know what conscience means, don't you?
你知道什么是良心，对吗？
Fuck you and your conscience!
去尼玛的良心！
You won't look me in the eye?
你都不好好看我一眼吗？
It's been three years.
已经三年了
You haven't come to visit for three whole years.
你已经三年没来了
You kicked me out.
你把我踢出去的
You haven't even called.
你甚至都没有打电话
You told me not to.
你告诉我不要打
I did, because you left that cushy job and went and became a cop!
是啊，因为你辞掉了那份轻松的工作，去当警察了!
What was all that education for?
这些教育是为了什么？
See what it's come to?
你看现在怎么样？
You might've gotten yourself into trouble.
你会惹上麻烦的
Your name, written on the foreheads of dead men.
你的名字，写在死者的额头上
Nevra...
I worked my ass off to get you through school.
我努力工作供你上学
I had to work as a cashier in addition to my day job.
我除了日常工作外还要做出纳员
When that didn't do it...
但当那些没起作用的时候…
You got married four times.
你结了四次婚
- I did it all for you. - For me?
-那都是为了你 -为我吗？
- So that you had a dad. - So that I didn't become a whore.
-那样你能有一个父亲 -因此我就不会成为妓女
Go on, say it. That's what you've always said.
继续说吧，这就是你一直说的
You were so scared I'd go astray. I never figured out why.
你好怕我会误入歧途  我一直不明白为什么
Do you want to become a whore?
你想成为妓女吗？
Why?
为什么？
Why would I?
我为什么会想？
You must've seen something deep within me.
你一定在我内心深处看到了什么
- Don't be silly. - You must have.
-别傻了 -你一定有
That's enough!
够了！
You got married four times for me!
你为我结了四次婚！
You saved me!
你救了我！
That was so selfless of you!
你真无私！
So selfless of you to always have a man around the house.
如此无私的你总会在屋子里围着一个男人
All you did to keep me from becoming a whore...
你做的一切都是为了不让我变成妓女……
Getting with new men before even leaving the last one.
在离开上一个人之前就与新男人相处
Shut up.
闭嘴
By the way...
顺便说说
I know you didn't ask, but my father's doing fine.
我知道你没问，但是我父亲很好
He didn't say hi, but he's fine.
他没有打招呼，但很好
You still call him your father?
你还称他为你父亲吗？
Your father's dead.
你父亲死了
That bastard called Yuksel...
那个叫Yuksel的混蛋
He isn't half the man your father was.
他不及你父亲的一半
He's the one who gave you these ideas.
是他给了你这些想法
He's the one who made you into a cop.
是他让你成为了警察
Why so angry, mom?
妈妈你为什么这么生气？
Huh?
?？
Tell me, why do you hate life so much?
告诉我，你为什么这么讨厌生活？
Why don't you love me?
你为什么不爱我？
Stop speaking nonsense.
别胡说
Then tell me you do.
那你告诉我
Say "I love you, my girl."
说“我爱你，我的女孩”
By the way, I hate the word "whore", you know.
顺便说一句，我讨厌“ 妓女”这个词
It feels so dirty when I say it.
说出来就觉得脏
You're the only one I can say it to.
我只能对你说这个词
I become someone else when I'm with you.
当我和你在一起时我变得不像我
Like a child. A naive, innocent child.
像孩子一样，天真无邪的孩子
You do that to me.
这就是你对我的影响
I love you too, mom.
妈妈  我也爱你
I love you too.
我也爱你
What's the emergency?
什么紧急情况？
I had a heart attack.
我得了心脏病
- Alright. Come on in. - Thank you.
-好吧，进来 -谢谢
A heart attack?
心脏病？
How's he doing now?
他现在还好吗？
He's fine, he just needs some rest.
他很好，他只需要休息一下
The doctor said his heart was strong.
医生说他的心很强壮
He's too full of anger to die.
他满腔怒火，还不能死
I was in the hospital, but something urgent came up.
我在医院里，但是出了一些紧急情况
I had to do that. I had to get there.
我必须要去做一件事
But on my way there, I forgot what I was supposed to do.
但是在去那里的路上，我忘记了应该做什么
Mr. Agah...
Agah先生
Excuse my bluntness, but you'd had a heart attack.
原谅我的直言不讳，但你得了心脏病
You were in the hospital. What could've been so urgent?
你在医院里有什么紧急的事？
It was my daughter Zuhal's birthday. I had to get her a present.
那是我女儿Zuhal的生日，我有礼物要送给她
- Your daughter's here? - I'm here now.
-你的女儿在这里？-我现在在这里
Looking for a job.
找工作
Still haven't found one.
什么都没找到
Not sure what I'll do.
不知道我该怎么办
I'd like to meet her.
我想见见她
- We haven't even spoken on the phone. - I know.
-我们甚至都没有打电话 -我知道
I'll come by unannounced, you know.
你知道我会不请自来的
It's not the end of the world.
这不是世界的尽头
- If you're unhappy, then get divorced. - I guess that's what we'll do.
-如果你不开心，那就离婚 -我想这就是我们要做的
I told Mebrure so many times to divorce him, but she wouldn't listen.
我跟Mebrure说过很多次让她离婚，但她不听
- We don't listen, sometimes. - Did it both to herself and to us.
-人们有时候就是不听 -自找苦吃
- I was collateral damage, as well. - My mom and dad were miserable.
-对我也有附带伤害 -我的父母都很痛苦
My dumb sister.
我愚蠢的妹妹
- Being dumb isn't good. - I'm in love, she said.
-装傻是不好的 -我恋爱了，她说
- I'm not even in love. - Your mom was so naive.
-我根本没有恋爱 -你妈妈太天真了
- She would believe anything.  - I don't believe, though!
-她什么都相信 -但我不相信！
So what?
所以呢？
I used to lie all the time, doc.
我以前一直撒谎，医生
When I was young.
我小的时候
I used to lie so often, it was second nature to me.
经常撒谎，这对我来说是第二天性
It was almost a mania.
快要疯了
Mebrure used to believe anything I'd say.
Mebrure曾经相信我会说的话
Deceiving her started feeling horrible.
后来欺骗她让我感到害怕
I hated myself.
我恨自己
I promised I'd never lie to her again.
我保证不会再对她说谎
I'd be as honest with everyone else as I was with myself.
我会像对待自己一样诚实对待其他人
Alas...
唉……
Once I was cursed with this disease...
一旦我被这种疾病诅咒
This forgetting disease called Alzheimer's...
这种称之为阿尔茨海默氏病的让人遗忘的疾病
That's when I started lying again.
我又开始撒谎了
You know what's the worst part about being a liar?
你知道做为骗子最糟糕的是什么？
Having to remember all the lies.
必须记住所有的谎言
What am I supposed to do now?
我现在该怎么办？
Call your cousin. We can call him together.
给你表哥打电话，我们可以一起打电话给他
He'll find you a job that suits you. OK?
他会找到适合你的工作，好吗？
You don't need your father. I'm right here for you.
你不需要留在你父亲身边，我就在这里
He's the one who needs us.
是他需要我们
He's never accepted it, but he's always been the one who needs us.
他一直都不承认，但他才是需要我们的人
He thought he could do no wrong.
他以为他不会做错事
Mebrure gave him everything she had.
Mebrure把一切都给了他
I'm losing my personality.
我正在失去我的人格
It's too much to bear.
太让人受不了了
Here's what we'll do.
接下来我们这样做
- You can't bear the truth, you lie. - Yes.
-你不能忍受真相，你在说谎 -是的
- We'll discover that moment together. - How are we going to do that?
-我们会一起发现那一刻的 -我们怎么做？
The moment you started running from reality.
从现实出发的那一刻
And why you keep running.
以及为什么你一直在逃避
That's what we'll go looking for.
那就是我们要寻找的
But I don't know why.
但我不知道为什么
You might not know.
你可能不知道
But your memory does.
但是你的记忆知道
Ask your memory.
问问你的记忆
Go into the past.
回顾过去
Go to the places that remind you of your past.
去那些能让您回想起过去的地方
Whatever it is that's scaring you
不管是什么使你恐惧
is hidden in your past.
都隐藏在你的过去
Find it, Mr. Agah.
找到它，Agah先生
Find the first truth that terrified you.
找到令你恐惧的真相
INCOMING CALL ATES ARBAY
Ates来电
Yes, Ates?
喂，Ates？
Is it time yet?
到时间了吗？
Time for what?
什么时间？
You've promised me an interview. Can we do it tonight?
您答应我的访谈，今晚可以做吗？
I'm busy, Ates. Another time.
我很忙，再约时间吧
I didn't let you down the last time you called.
上次你找我的时候我可没让你失望哦
Fine. Where do we meet?
好吧，我们在哪里见面？
Give me some space, please.
请给我一些空间，谢谢
- Huh? - Take off.
-嗯？-走开
Take off where?
去哪里？
I'm expecting someone. There's an empty seat over there.
我在等人，那边也有座位
I'm not going anywhere!
我哪都不去！
My dearly departed wife will be here soon.
我亲爱的亡妻很快就要来了
Go on.
去吧
Mebrure!
I saw that.
我看见了
Don't you have enough?
还没拍够吗？
Don't look into the camera. Look over there.
不要看镜头  看那边
That's the last one.
很快结束了
Just like that.
就这样
Keep that pose.
保持这个姿势
Is it done?
好了吗？
No.
没有
Stay just like that.
保持住
Just like that.
就这样
Stay...
别动
Almost there...
快好了……
I've got it.
拍完了
Finally.
总算好了
Let's get started on that interview.
让我们开始这次访谈吧
Deva?
Where have you been, Deva?
你去哪了？
I told my mom I was going out.
我告诉妈妈我要出去
She didn't ask where you'd be?
她没有问你会去哪里？
- I don't explain myself anymore. - Who did you take after, I wonder.
-我不再为自己辩解了 -我不知道你像谁
- You're so weird. - I know.
-你好奇怪 -我知道
You know...
你知道……
I've been hearing about
我经常听说
increased drug use among teenagers.
青少年吸毒人数一直在增加
- You don't do that, right. - Of course not, grandpa.
-你不吸毒，对吧？ -当然不吸
Good. That's good to hear.
很好  很好
How about booze?
喝酒吗？
Only if you're buying.
你买我就喝
I've got it. Thank you.
我知道了，谢谢
I want to speak to your former colleagues, as well.
我还想跟你以前的同事聊聊
From the company you used to work for.
你曾经工作过的公司
You can ask me whatever you'd like to know.
你想知道什么可以直接问我
Why?
为什么？
Because I know them all, but none of them know me.
因为我了解他们，但没人了解我
Fine. Tell me something you'd like to tell me.
很好，告诉我一些你想告诉我的事
That's the only question that fits someone like you.
那是唯一适合你的问题
What would you like to say, Nevra?
你想告诉我什么事？
What have you been up to today?
今天做了些什么啊？
Today...
今天
I went to the place where I proposed to your grandmother. It was 40 years ago.
我去了40年前我向你祖母求婚的地方
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢你 -不客气
Though.
虽然
I didn't propose this time.
这次没有求婚
What I'd like to say...
我想说什么
Is that I'm going to get that killer.
我要抓到那个杀手
Wherever he runs to.
无论他跑到哪里
Wherever he hides.
无论他躲在哪里
I'm going to find him, and arrest him.
我都要找到他并逮捕他
You don't believe me?
你不相信我吗
I don't believe in anything anymore.
我什么都不相信了
I don't even believe in myself.
我甚至不再相信自己
But I so need to believe in someone.
但是我需要相信一个人
I've been spending my years in the back pages of the newspaper
我多年来一直在报纸的封底上度过
in that DJ booth,
在那个DJ位上
at those receptions I attend just to get fucked up,
在那些招待会上
at the shitty premieres of lame-ass movies.
在烂片的首映式上
Feels like I'm rotting from the inside.
感觉就像我由内而外腐烂
I can't even bear to look in the direction of those photos.
我甚至不忍心看那些照片的方向
You still keep them up.
你还留着它们
They're still there.
还在那里
I told a lie that day. Maybe the first lie of my whole life.
那天我说了一个谎言，也许是我一生中的第一个谎言
"Mebrure," I said,
“ Mebrure，”我说，
"I'll make you happy."
我会让你幸福
"Mebrure, take my hand, and let's get up off this bench,
“拉着我的手，让我们从凳子上站起来
and -excuse my French-let's get the fuck out of here."
让我们他妈的离开这里” 原谅我说了脏话
Without a care in the world.
没有一点牵挂
Or...
或者
"Mebrure, forget you ever knew me..."
“宝贝，忘了你曾经认识我”
I'm not made for marriage.
“我不是个适合结婚的人”
"I'll only make you unhappy."
“我只会给你带来不幸”
Something like that.
像这样
You can't hold your liquor at all, can you?
你根本不能喝酒，是吗？
You're already seeing double. Where are you...
你已经看重影了，你在哪……
Go talk to her. Go on.
去跟她聊天吧
Think about what you're going to say. You'll kick yourself later otherwise.
想好了再说话，不然你会后悔的
A miserable soul, desperate for attention.
一个悲惨的灵魂，渴望得到关注
The biggest favor you can do for such a sociopath is to talk about him.
你能为这样的反社会变态做的最大的帮助就是谈论他
But you've been on this case ever since the murders started.
但是，自谋杀案发生以来，您一直在关注这个案件
Isn't that a favor to him, then?
那不是对他有利吗？
I'm a journalist.
我是记者
I have to inform the public.
我必须通知公众
Ates, aren't you afraid at all that the murderer will target you?
Ates，你一点都不害怕凶手会把你作为目标吗？
Look...
看
Just like he has his eyes on me,
就像他看着我一样
I have my eyes on the perimeter of my house.
我也能在房子周围看到你
Remember, no one can turn invisible.
记住，没有人可以隐身
Least of all someone so deranged.
至少如此疯狂的人不会
This is what I do, you see.
这就是我所做的，你看到了吗
I'm in show business.
我在做演员
The show serves one purpose only... To make people forget.
表演只不过是为了让人们忘记
I'm in the forgetting business.
我正在忘记事情
- You're being too harsh on yourself. - It's how it works.
-你对自己太苛刻了-这就是它的运作方式
Let's say there's a massacre somewhere.
假设某处发生大屠杀
There's an assassination, but the assassin never gets caught.
发生一次暗杀，但刺客从未被抓住
I make people forget about them.
我能让人们忘记他们
Has there been a huge fraud? Call for me and I'll make them forget.
发生过大型诈骗案吗？找我，我会让他们忘记
How? How do you make them forget?
怎么做？如何使他们忘记？
With stories such as this one about the murderer.
像这样一个关于凶手的故事
I spin a fairy tale.
我编了一个童话故事
They all listen with bated breath.
大家都屏息静听
He gets caught and another one emerges.
他被抓了之后另一个人出现了
He gets caught, and another one.
又被抓了，然后又出现一个
I tell all their stories. But you know what I don't do?
我给他们讲故事，但是你知道我不做什么吗？
How come so many people are licensed to carry guns?
为什么这么多人可以携带枪支?
How come people can access guns so easily?
为什么人们可以如此轻易地获得枪支?
I never talk about that.
我从没说过
You got it?
你明白了吗？
If you want to make people forget about the gun,
如果你想让人们忘记枪
all you have to do is talk about the victim.
你所要做的就是谈论受害者
But I'm not doing it anymore.
但我不再这样做了
I've had it up to here.
到此为止
What will you do?
你会怎么做？
May I curse?
我可以讲脏话吗？
I'll fuck them up.
我会干他妈的
I won't let people forget.
我不会让人们忘记
When did you decide on that?
你什么时候决定的?
Today.
今天
As I was shooting you, to be precise.
准确地说，当我给你拍照时
You're so sweet.
你好骚啊
The car...
车！
Zuhal...
I've been thinking.
我一直在想
We should get you a place.
我们应该给你找个地方
A place of your own.
属于你自己的地方
You'd both be more comfortable that way.
那样你们俩会更舒服
He'll have his own room, at least.
他至少会有自己的房间
I can cover the rent until you get a job.
我能负担租金直到你找到工作
When you said you'd been thinking, I thought you'd be like...
当你说你一直在想的时候，我以为你会像
"Let's sell the apartment downstairs and get you a place of your own."
“我把楼下的公寓卖了，给你找个地方住。”
Something like that.
像这样
It's not like I haven't been doing that.
我不是没想过
Number four, covered your high school.
四号房间，用于支付你高中的费用
Number six, your college.
六号，大学的费用
Number seven, your master's in London.
七号，你的伦敦硕士学位
Number three, as you know, went towards your mother's treatment.
如你所知，三号支付了你母亲的治疗费用
I'm all alone in this huge building now.
我现在一个人在这个巨大的大楼里
- We still have Number eight, though. - I told you I rent that out.
-不过我们还有八号 -我告诉你我把它租出去了
We can tell the tenants we need to sell it. I can talk to them.
我们可以告诉租户我们需要卖掉，可以和他们交谈
You can't talk to them. They're using it for storage.
不能跟他们谈，他们在用房间做仓库
They live abroad.
他们住在国外
I can call them, then. Just give me their number.
我可以打电话给他们，给我他们的电话
Of course. We can sell this apartment, as well.
当然我们也可以卖这套公寓
You can put me in a home.
你可以把我放在家里
Even better, you can put me out on the street.
也可以把我扔到大街上
Do you realize how selfish you sound?
你知道你听起来有多自私吗？
This building is named after your mother.
这座建筑以你母亲的名字命名
How can you be so ready to let it go?
你怎么能这么轻易放手？
We should be grateful to my departed grandfather, right?
我们应该感谢我已故的祖父，对吗？
For giving this building to my mother.
谢谢他把这栋楼交给我妈妈
What would we do if he hadn't?
如果没有他我们该怎么办？
What would you do? What would I? What would Deva?
你怎么办？我怎么办？Deva怎么办？
Say what you mean to say.
说出来
What is it you'd like to say, exactly?
您到底想说什么？
Don't stick your nose where it doesn't belong.
不要多管闲事
See how I don't stick my nose into your business?
学学我，从不多管闲事
See how I never ask about why you got divorced from your husband?
我从没问过你为什么与丈夫离婚？
See how I keep my mouth shut? How about you try it out for once?
学我怎么闭嘴，你尝试一下如何？
Ask me, dad.
问我啊
Ask me. Why don't you?
问什么不问呢？
Why don't you ask?
你为什么不问？
Ask me why Deva and I came here.
问我为什么Deva和我来这里
Ask me why he wants to get divorced.
问我为什么他要离婚
Come on! But you won't, will you?
来吧！但是你不会问，对吗？
You know why you won't?
你知道为什么你不会问吗？
Because you hate listening to other people's problems.
因为你讨厌听别人的问题
It's the thing you hate the most.
这是你最讨厌的事情
Someone telling you of their troubles.
别人告诉你他们的麻烦事
Dad...
爸
You can't even bear it when people are sick around you.
你甚至不能忍受周围的人生病
Remember the times I had fevers as a kid?
还记得我小时候发烧吗？
Remember what you did? Do you remember?
记得你做了什么吗？
I'll remind you. You left.
我来提醒你！你离开了！
You left the house.
你离开了家
I used to pray with all my might not to get sick.
我曾经尽力祈祷不生病
Not to get fevers so that my father didn't get mad at me.
不要发烧，这样我的父亲就不会生我的气
You didn't look after mom, either.
你也没照顾妈妈
The nurses did. I did. father didn't get mad at me.
护士照顾了，我和医生照顾了
But you never did.
但是你从来没有
You'd come to the hospital.
你去医院
I'd tell you, "Dad, mom's dying."
我会告诉你，“爸爸，妈妈快死了”
You'd say "No."
你会说“不”
"She's doing great. Mom's doing great."
“她很好，妈妈很好”
Because that's what you want to hear.
因为那是你想听到的
Everything's great. No problems whatsoever.
一切都很好没有任何问题
Everything's perfect.
一切都很完美
I'll say it if it will help. We have no problems, dad.
如果有用的话，我就说出来  我们没问题，爸爸
You're perfect. I'm perfect.
你是完美的  我是完美的
Deva's perfect.
Deva也是完美的
Life's perfect.
完美的人生
Good.
好
That's good.
那很好
Agah Beyoglu.
这里是Agha Beyoglu
- Agah? - Nukhet!
-Agah？-Nukhet！
How are you?
你好吗？
I was just thinking about you.
我刚刚还在想你
I was able to find some tickets.
我搞到了几张票
- Were you now? - It's tonight. Would you like to join me?
-是吗？-今天晚上你想一起吗？
Sure.
当然
- What is it? - We're ready.
-什么事？-我们准备好了
I'll be right there.
我马上到
Hand these out to the guys.
把这些交给他们
Alright...
好了……
Where's Nevra?
Nevra呢？
She got a tip from somewhere. She went to the courthouse to look into it.
她从某个地方得到了线报，去了法院进行调查
You know Mehmet Yurtgil, the judge?
你知道Mehmet Yurtgil吗？
He was known for taking bribes.
他因受贿而闻名
She's looking into the suspects that were wronged.
她在调查被冤枉的嫌疑犯
She thinks someone might've took revenge on him.
她认为有人可能会对他报仇
Alright then. Anyway,
好吧，不管怎样
I have the ballistics report right here. Here's the situation:
我这里有弹道报告，结果是这样：
The gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi
用来杀死Naimhan Turedi的枪
does not match the one used to kill Mehmet Yurtgil.
与用来杀死Mehmet Yurtgil的那只不匹配
That gun wasn't registered anywhere. However...
那枪没有在任何地方注册
We have some leads on the gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi.
我们在用来杀死Naimhan Turedi的枪上有一些线索
Someone was shot and wounded with that gun in 2001.
2001年有人用那把枪开枪并受伤
The gun was seized, and is supposed to be
枪应该是被没收了
in the Ard?chan municipality police department's evidence locker.
存放在Ard?chan市警察局的证据储物柜中
But it's gone! Why's that?
但是它消失了，为什么呢？
Because that evidence locker no longer exists.
因为那个证据储物柜已经没有了
How about... That sleazeball you were looking into?
你调查的那个混蛋怎么样？
He had nothing to do with it.
他跟这些都没有关系
Alright. Now...
好吧……
The individual who did all this shit...
做这些事的人
Let's call him Tufan for now.
我们暂时叫他Tufan
Tufan gets into the evidence locker.
Tufan进入证据储物柜
He burglarizes the locker. Then...
他盗窃了储物柜，然后
He burns the place down to make it look like the mafia did it.
他把地方烧了，使它看起来像黑手党做的一样
So he's not interested in killing just anyone.
所以他对杀人不感兴趣
He's not a regular serial killer.
他不是常规的连环杀手
Since he's in possession of so many guns,
既然他拥有这么多枪，
and assuming he's not interested in selling them,
并假设他不准备卖枪
welcome to your own personal hells.
那么就很明显了
He's going to commit a massacre.
他将要开始屠杀
Unless we catch him first.
除非我们先抓到他
MARCH 18 SUNDAY
3月18日 周日
Here. Here's my resumé.
这是我的简历
Thank you for agreeing to see me. I know you're busy.
谢谢你同意见我  我知道你很忙
It's an honor to meet you.
很荣幸见到你
This means nothing.
这没什么意义
This is it.
就是这个
- Where have you been? Austria? - Australia.
-您去过哪里？奥地利？-澳大利亚
I just got back.
我刚回来
You're just in time.
你来的很及时
Melahat, my secretary for 20 years,
我的秘书跟了我20年了，
was retired just last week.
上周刚刚退休
Coincidence, I guess.
我猜是巧合吧
There are no coincidences.
没有巧合
Because life itself is a coincidence.
因为生活本身就是巧合
A man locks the door to his house for 99 days.
一个人连续锁门99天
On the 100th day, he forgets to lock the door.
在第100天，他忘记锁门
The thief repents.
小偷很后悔
He ignores the house for those 99 days,
在那99天内，他无视这所房子，
but finds the door unlocked on the 100th day.
但在第100天发现门没锁
The days line up.
每天都排着队
What do you call that?
你怎么说？
A coincidence?
巧合？
No.
不是
What is it?
那是什么？
It's life.
这就是生活
You're a fast learner, Zuhal.
你学得很快  Zuhal
- Celik. - Beyoglu. My surname's Beyoglu.
-Celik - Beyoglu  我姓Beyoglu
I'm getting divorced.
我要离婚了
Do you know Agah Beyoglu? Is he a relative of yours?
你知道Agah Beyoglu吗？他是你的亲戚吗？
He's my father.
他是我父亲
Incredible.
难以置信
Now this, this isn't life. This is coincidence.
这不是生命这是巧合
How is he doing? Well, I hope?
他最近好吗？
He's well, of course. How do you know him?
他很好，当然，你怎么认识他？
From Kambura. Where else?
当然是Kambura  还能是哪里？
- Prosecutor? - Did you know about this?
-检察官？-你知道这件事吗？
KILLER OR VICTIM?
是杀手还是受害者？
I did. It was Nevra's idea. I told her to go ahead with it.
我知道  那是Nevra的主意  我告诉她继续做下去
That was a stupid risk to take.
这是一个愚蠢的冒险
What if Tufan gets caught and everything is revealed?
如果Tufan被抓了并且一切都暴露了怎么办？
What then?
然后会怎样呢？
Tufan has no connection either to Nevra or to any of the victims.
Tufan与Nevra或任何受害者都没有任何关系
That's why I approved the news article.
所以我批准了这篇新闻
There's someone else involved.
还有其他人参与
Whoever it is that's helping Tufan
不管是谁在帮Tufan
will panic when he realizes that we're on his trail.
当他意识到我们在追踪他时，他会感到恐慌
It's your call.
是你的电话
But I'm uneasy.
可是我很不安
I'm not sure getting Nevra involved in this was the right idea.
我不确定让Nevra参与这个案子是否正确
Do you have any better ideas? No?
您有更好的主意吗？
Then we proceed.
那我们继续
Did you tell Firuz?
你有没有告诉Firuz？
I did. He's supervising Nevra.
告诉他了  他在监督Nevra
Where's Nevra now?
Nevra现在在哪里？
I told her she'd be kicked off the force if it was discovered.
我告诉她如果被发现  她会被踢出警队
She's lying to me. Told me her mom was sick. Went to Kambura.
她对我撒谎  告诉我她妈妈生病了  去了Kambura
That's where she lives.
那是她家
Isn't there where the second victim was born?
第二个受害者不就是在那里出生的吗？
That's right. She could be looking into it.
是的  她可能正在调查
Good. We have some leads, then.
好  我们有了一些线索
We do but I can't bear the thought of using one of my people as bait.
但我不忍心用我的人当诱饵
Are you having her followed? You are. So what's the problem?
你不是有人在跟着她吗？有什么不放心的？
Look here, Tolga.
注意  Tolga
He's not going to stop killing people anytime soon.
他近期不会停止杀人
Who's supposed to catch him? You are.
谁应该抓住他？是你
What's the only lead we have? Nevra.
唯一的线索是什么？Nevra
If you take Nevra off the case,
如果你将Nevra拒之门外，
it won't matter whether it was Tufan or someone else.
不管是Tufan还是其他人
You'll never catch the murderer.
你永远都不会抓住凶手
Someone's committing these murders just to get Nevra to try to solve them.
有人犯下这些谋杀罪只是为了让内夫拉设法解决他们
MAYA'S COSTUME WORLD
玛雅的装扮世界
Those things will kill you, you know.
烟会杀死你的，你知道吧
You don't have to throw it out. Give me one.
别扔，给我来一支
- Any leads from the courthouse? - No.
-法院有线索了吗？-没有
I have a light.
我有火
My father's lighter.
我父亲的打火机
He passed it down to me the day he stopped smoking.
他戒烟的那一天把它传给了我
I asked him what I was supposed to do with it. I didn't even smoke.
我问他我该怎么办，我那时还没开始抽烟
I picked it up that day.
我在那天开始抽烟
I picked up smoking the day my father quit. Ridiculous.
我父亲戒烟那一天我开始抽烟
It was my mom that encouraged me to smoke, actually.
实际上是我妈妈鼓励我抽烟
She told me it was alright if I smoked, but that I shouldn't be sneaky about it.
她告诉我如果我抽烟是可以的，但是不应该偷偷摸摸
I didn't smoke, but I couldn't tell her.
我不会抽烟，但是我不能告诉她
I sat across from her and lit one up just to get to spend some time with her.
我坐在她的对面，点燃了一根烟，与她共度时光
That's how I started smoking.
我就是这样开始吸烟的
Just to do the same thing as her at the same time as she did.
只是为了和她在一起做点什么事
How is she? Better?
她好吗？
Better. She's better.
好多了
It must be hard, living so far away from each other.
应该很难吧，彼此相距太远
- I see her from time to time. - Good. Don't stop seeing her.
-我时不时能见到她 -好  不要不见她
My father's dead now.
我父亲已经死了
This is all that's left of him.
这就是他剩下的一切
MUNIR - MY LOVELY CAT
MUNIR -我可爱的猫
I'm so scared of death, Munir.
我好怕死，穆尼尔
In fact, I'll tell you a secret.
其实我会告诉你一个秘密
I'd be OK with it even if everyone on earth died
即使地球上的每个人都死了，我也没关系
and I were the only one left.
我是唯一剩下的一个
I mean...
我的意思是
I'm even willing to face such loneliness.
我甚至愿意面对这样的寂寞
What if I still remember all I've done in the afterlife?
如果我来世还记得我所做的一切怎么办？
I couldn't bear that.
我不能忍受
I couldn't.
我不能
Grandpa!
爷爷！
What are you doing? Shut the door!
你在做什么？关上门！
What...
什么
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Shut the door!
关上门！
Such bad timing.
来得真不是时候
Tell your mom I have some errands to run tonight.
告诉你妈妈  我今晚有事要出门
Get yourself a cell phone, please.
求你买个电话吧
I have a phone.
我有电话
By the way, let me introduce you guys. Suveyda, my grandfather.
顺便给您介绍一下，这是Suveyda
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你
I hope you're using protection.
我希望你做了保护措施
I can't handle another child.
我无法应付另一个孩子
- I'm not staying. - What are you doing?
-我不能停车 -你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I forgot I had something to do.
我忘了我有事要做
I have something to do. I'd forgotten. I'm not coming in.
我有事  可做我忘了  我不能去了
You can make a u-turning side the car park.
你可以在停车场的另一边掉头
Could you tell the car behind me to let me pass in reverse?
你能告诉后面那辆车的车主让我倒车过去吗?
There are too many cars waiting.
有太多车在等
- But I'm... - Open up your boot, please.
-但我……-请打开你的后备箱
But I'm in a hurry. That'll be a lot of wasted time.
但是我很着急  那会浪费很多时间
It's how the procedure works. I don't make the rules.
这是工作程序  规则不是我定的
The car doesn't run on natural gas, I assure you.
我向你保证，这辆车不是用天然气发动的
I believe you, but I still have to look. Give me your keys, please.
我相信你，但我还是要看看  请把你的钥匙给我。
The boot's broken. It doesn't open.
后备箱坏了  打不开
- Hand me your keys, please. - It's broken, I'm telling you.
-请把钥匙交给我  -坏了，我告诉你
Fine. Give me a minute.
好  我等一下
Broken.
坏了
I've tried so many times, but it won't open.
我已经尝试了很多次了，但是打不开
- Let me try, sir. - It won't open.
-让我试试，先生  -它不会打开
- But, it won't open  - Let me try.
-但是，它打不开  -让我试试
Look! You break it, you buy it.
看！你弄坏了，赔钱吧
- Forgive me, Hajji. - It's fine.
-请原谅哈吉（到麦加朝圣过的伊斯兰教徒）  -算了
- I have to follow the orders. - I understand.
-我必须遵守命令  -我明白
My uncle's a Hajji as well. He just got back.
我叔叔也是哈吉  他刚回来
May Allah bless him.
愿真主保佑他
Amen. Amen.
阿门  阿门
They say there's a killer on the loose. We have strict orders.
他们说有个杀手在逃  我们有严格的命令
How many times have I told you there was nothing to see?
我告诉过你很多次了  没有什么可看的
- Please forgive me for prying.  - It's fine.
-请原谅  -很好
Nobody believes in people anymore.
人与人之间最基本的信任在哪里
Such a tragedy!
真是悲哀！
Forgive me for being late, Nukhet.
Nukhet，原谅我迟到了
I ran into so many delays.
我遇到了些麻烦事
- Don't mention it. You're here now. - You look great.
-别说了  你现在到了  -看起来很棒
- Thank you. So do you. - Thank you.
-谢谢你  你也是  -谢谢
- We should go in, it's about to start. - Of course. After you.
-我们快进去吧  快开始了 -当然，在您之后
- Welcome. - Good evening.
-欢迎  -晚上好
- Thank you. - Your seats are right over there.
-谢谢  -您的座位就在那边
- Thank you. - Thank you, guys.
-谢谢  -谢谢你们
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
What are you doing? Who are you?
你在做什么？你是谁？
Answer me!
回答我！
No mortal can take this life.
没有人能夺走生命
They can't bear it.
他们不能忍受
They deny everything.
他们否认一切
They lie.
他们说谎
They keep quiet.
他们保持安静
Or they throw it all up.
或丢弃
Or they plot.
或阴谋
Or they run from it.
或逃避
Or they steal.
或偷窃
Or they break.
或破产
Or they give birth.
或生育
Or they suffocate.
或窒息
Or they get drunk.
或醉酒
Or they fall in love.
或恋爱
Or they stop moving,
或停止
and die little by little.
一点一点地死去
They wilt.
他们枯萎
They question.
他们质疑
They get mad.
他们生气
They get resentful.
他们不满
They ejaculate.
他们射精
They seize up.
他们抓住
They believe.
他们相信
They get created.
他们创造
They fight.
他们打架
They get wounded.
他们受伤
They try...
他们尝试
They try, and get it wrong.
他们尝试然后错了
They try,
他们尝试，
and get it wrong.
然后错了
Try and get it wrong.
尝试弄错
Conscience resembles the gut.
良心类似于内心
It keeps working away even while you're asleep.
即使您在睡觉时，它也在不停地工作
No matter how much you deny your conscience,
无论您有多么否认自己的良心，
that horrible murder you've committed
你犯下的可怕的谋杀案
always becomes the rope you get hung by.
会永远成为你被吊住的绳索
It wraps around your neck,
它缠绕在你的脖子上，
the oily pieces of rope your victim has for hands.
你受害者手上的油乎乎的绳子
You seldom know what it is you've murdered.
你基本不知道你杀的是什么
But you still keep hanging yourself every night in your dreams.
但你仍然每天晚上都在梦中吊死自己
The gut resembles the conscience.
内心很像良心
If you're looking to empty it of its contents,
如果您要清空其中的内容
you'll find somewhere to do it.
你会找到一个地方做
Man...
人
Tries, and gets it wrong.
尝试，并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
人尝试并弄错了
Tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
Agah, are you alright?
Agah，你还好吗？
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
Tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
This is art?
这是艺术？
Sorry.
抱歉
They call it art? What is this?
他们称之为艺术？这是什么？
Tries and gets it wrong.
尝试并弄错了
That's the first time I've left a play before the curtain.
那是我第一次在结束前离开
I thought it was ridiculous.
我认为这很荒谬
It's good that we left early. I was bored out of my mind.
幸好离开的早，我要无聊死了
I've been meaning to tell you something, but I've never found the right time.
我一直想告诉你一些事情，但是我一直没找到合适的机会
When I came to visit you at the hospital, your daughter Zuhal was devastated.
当我来医院看望您时，您的女儿Zuhal似乎遭受了重创
- Did she say something inconsiderate. - No. Just the opposite.
-她说了些不体面的话 -不，恰恰相反
She said something that moved me.
她说了一些让我感动的事
You told her that you were staying over at my place that night you had your accident.
你告诉她那天晚上你在我家过夜了
You said I was your girlfriend.
你说我是你女朋友
At least that's the impression she'd gotten.
至少那是她的印象
- What did you say? - I said that you were with me.
-你说什么？-我说你和我在一起
I'm sure you had your reasons.
我确信你有你的理由
- I wouldn't speak against you. - You're so kind.
-我不会揭穿你-你真好
Thank you.
谢谢
I've been living on my own for such a long time...
我独居了很长时间
I've gotten used to it.
我已经习惯了
But it does get boring from time to time.
但有时也会变得无聊
I go out on my own sometimes,
有时候我一个人出去玩
but I don't want them to worry about me.
但我不想让他们担心我
Forgive me for putting you on the spot like that.
请原谅我那样让你为难
You know what I said to myself?
你知道我内心怎么想吗？
I wish he'd really stayed over.
我希望他真的能来我家
DEAR NEVRA ELMAS, WE WISH YOU A HAPPY BIRTHDAY. ARTI BANK.
亲爱的NEVRA ELMAS，祝你生日快乐  ARTI BANK
This cake's delicious. Did you buy it?
这蛋糕很好吃  你买的吗？
Yes, Selim. Enjoy.
是的，Selim  吃吧
I'll get you one on your birthday.
你生日那天我给你买一个
- When's that, by the way? - Don't worry about it.
-什么时候？-别操心了
- About what we talked about... - What was that?
-我们讨论过的…… -什么？
That house on the hill?
那座山上的房子？
Nesrin hates talking about it, that's why I couldn't say anything.
Nesrin讨厌说起它，这就是为什么我什么也不能说的原因
But there was a tragedy there.
但是那里曾发生过一起惨案
It was ten years ago.
十年前
You were away at college.
你去上大学了
A family came and moved in to that house on the hill.
一家人搬到山上的那所房子里
Shortly thereafter, there were a few burglaries.
此后不久，发生了几起盗窃案
Everybody blamed the new family.
每个人都怪罪新搬来的那家人
One night, the people worked themselves into a frenzy.
一天晚上，人们变得疯狂起来
Young, old, everyone...
年轻人，老人，所有人……
They decided to drive the family away.
他们决定驱逐这家人
They surrounded the house.
他们包围了房子
Shouting, throwing rocks...
大喊  并且扔石头
The family was too scared to come out of the house.
那家人太害怕了不敢出门
And then, I don't know who, but someone threw a torch at the house.
然后，我不知道是谁，但是有人把火把扔到了屋子里
It flared up...
点着了
and burned the house down.
把房子烧了
Five children inside.
里面有五个孩子
And the mom and dad.
还有爸爸妈妈
They all burned up.
他们都被烧死了
Who threw the torch?
谁扔的火把？
No one would talk.
没有人会说
The police interrogated all of them, but no one would say anything.
警察审问了他们所有人，但是没人愿意说
It was completely forgotten after a while.
过了没多久，就被完全遗忘了
Everyone had stopped talking about it.
每个人都不再谈论
The house is still up there, burned to a crisp.
房子还在那儿，烧焦了
No one even bothered to tear it down.
甚至没有人愿意拆掉它
No one is bothered by it. They might walk by it,
没有人为此烦恼  他们只是路过
but they don't want to think about it, so they don't even notice it.
但他们不去想它，所以他们甚至都没有注意到
Was Naimhan Turedi there on that night?
那天晚上，Naimhan Turedi在那里吗？
Of course.
当然
All his friends, his relatives, everyone he knew was there.
他所有的朋友，他的亲戚，他认识的每个人都在那里
Sefer was there. Yakup and his uncle, as well.
Sefer也在那  Yakup和他的叔叔都在
They were drunk.
他们喝醉了
They'd gotten smashed at R?za's place.
他们在R?za的家喝醉了
How do you know about it?
你怎么知道的？
It haunts my dreams.
我经常梦到
It didn't use to,
以前不这样的
but people change as they get older.
但是随着年龄的增长人们会改变
Easy to say...
说起来容易
Seven people were killed.
七人被杀
The children were so small.
孩子都还很小
Who threw the torch, Selim?
谁仍的火把，Selim？
I didn't see him!
我没看到！
I...
我……
I only threw a single stone.
我只扔了一块石头
Is this a bad time?
现在过去好吗？
TODAY IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY I GOT HER A BIRTHDAY PRESENT
今天是NEVRA的生日  我有一件礼物送给她